[Music]
making an advertising claim that a
product provides a health related
benefit requires a higher level of
supporting evidence than for many other
advertising claims
an advertiser must be able to provide
competent and reliable scientific
evidence to support their health-related
claim
for example a claim that a lozenge
soothes coughs would require competent
and reliable scientific evidence as
support but evidence supporting a claim
that the lozenge has an improved taste
does not need to meet that standard
the national advertising division
follows the federal trade commission's
definition for competent and reliable
scientific evidence
the ftc's definition is flexible but for
claims that a product can cure mitigate
or treat a disease a randomized
placebo-controlled study on human beings
that reach statistical significance and
yield clinically meaningful results will
often be required
scientific evidence used to support a
health claim should translate into
real-world benefits for consumers that
relate directly to the performance
attributes promised by advertising
other evidence such as in vitro studies
or animal studies may be considered if
experts in the relevant area agree they
are sufficient to support the claim for
example when human studies are
infeasible there is no requirement that
any claim be supported by a particular
number of studies the quality of
supporting evidence is more important
than the quantity some health benefit
claims are phrased as establishment
claims that promise there is a
particular level of scientific evidence
that proves the claim
these claims might say that the product
is clinically proven or that tests show
a particular benefit is provided for
these claims an advertiser needs to
possess at least the level of
substantiation it advertises